

# **Career Summary**

## Orange, Warsaw, Poland

## **Nov 2018-Present**

#### **Tech Lead**

Flex app is a new, digital first operator created from scratch at Orange. The user has full control of their contract, which is not only cancellable on request but allows the user to switch plans and packages at any time. The whole project was treated as a sort of StartUp within Orange and it went public only 2 years from its conception. I've joined the Payments team which integrates 3rd party payment providers by adding control flows and ensuring consistency and security to monetary transactions. The position includes some DevOps work, 3rd party APIs integration and own logic implementation in Java. Technologies used include SpringBoot, Java 8, PostgresDB, Unit Testing in Spock within an ecosystem that includes Kubernetes, Vault, Spring Cloud Config, GoCD, E2E tests, Gitlab and GitlabCI; some Ansible Scripting plus python and NodeJS tools.

## Scanbots, Warsaw, Poland

## Oct 2017-Aug 2018

#### **Tech Lead**

Scanbots' goal was to make use of long-range drones for the monitoring of linear infrastructures, such as Electrical Networks, Oil & Gas Pipes, roads, etc. By integrating with state-of-the-art Drone manufacturers, Scanbots developed the software that integrated multiple sensors like Photo, thermal, near-infrared cameras and a LiDAR; GPS & IMUs for accurate spatial localisation. Such data needed to be sanitized, filtered, analyzed and exposed to clients. We developed a platform based in micro-services that would import, correlate, expose and export all data whilst storing it in a secure way. GIS technologies like PostGIS, GDAL, Leaflet.js, OpenSeaDragon and Potree were put in place to display images and point cloud data online. The platform's goal was to become the input to a Semi-supervised learning algorithm that would eventually find anomalies in images automatically, thanks to computer vision & machine learning techniques.

## Palo IT, Paris, France

Jan 2015-Sep 2017

#### **Senior Software Developer**

Carrefour

Sep 2016 - Sep 2017

Stock handling application which updates stock quantities from online sales in real-time by aggregating data from multiple sources. Async messaging with Kafka. Distributed DBs (Cassandra, Couchbase) Performance indexing in ElasticSearch. Middleware Proxying with NodeJS and Nginx. Web Dashboard to follow up metrics in Vue.js Integration Tests written in Python with Paramiko Java 8 and Unit Testing with Spock (Groovy) Deployment scripting Ansible CI with Jenkins

**Boursorama** 

Jul 2016 - Aug 2016



Created a Node.js API and a Web application in AngularJS V.1 to track functional and technical metrics issued by the underlying Datalake. Fraud and Marketing dashboards ElasticSearch & Cassandra data aggregation in Node.js

SACEM Jan 2015 – Jul 2016

Core business project for our client and first Agile one for them. The team developed a solution to easily handle errors in payments issued for several reasons. The system integrated manual, semi-automatic and automatic scenarios. Frontend in AngularJS V.1, backend in Java with Spring, Hibernate, Guava, Swagger, Lombok, Lucene, Oracle. BDD with Cucumber and TDD.

## eSpatial, Dublin, Ireland

Feb 2014 - Aug 2014

#### **Senior JAVA Developer**

Part of a multinational team developing a GIS oriented solution for visualizing clients data. Bug fixing and new features implementation using jQuery, backbone, underscore.js, handlebars. Java 7, Oracle 11g Spatial, Gradle, Git; Agile environment. Proposed and implemented PoC peer-reviewing with Gerrit.

# Globant, Buenos Aires, Argentina

May 2011 - Dec 2013

#### **Senior JAVA Developer**

**Google Finance Datawarehouse** 

Nov 2011 - Dec 2013

ETL creation and maintenance for Global internal financial data. Large datasets handling with Flume Java (Google's implementation) Google toolset and architecture experience: Map Reduce, Bigtable, Borg, Protocol Buffers, parallel computing job tuning, reporting, basic Python, etc. Full release schedule follow up, generating new versions and fixes based in continuous integration framework. Completed a personal project for an in-company client which required a ground up ETL style solution. Part of an international team lead from the US (Mountain View and Ann Arbor). Traveled twice to Google Headquarters in Silicon Valley. Exposure to Pentaho and Kettle.

Cablevision Jun 2011 - Jul 2011

Solo-consultant project to speed up bills processing on client site Full profiling and analysis of existing code and configuration Fixed bottlenecks and tuned up JVM and GC Processing times lowered from ~3 days to ~2 hours



## IBM, Dublin, Ireland

Jul 2010 - Dec 2010

#### **Java Developer**

Special project for a world-known Brewery. Real-time tracking of production chain anomalies to alert if certain SLAs were not met. Part of an English speaking multicultural environment and agile methodology. Direct user surveying (by phone, email, chat and in person). Experience with Mongo DB, DB2, LambdaJ, Web technologies, Spring, Hibernate, etc.

# Accenture, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Feb 2007 - Dec 2009

#### Trainee -> Senior Analyst/Technical Leader

After the merging of 3 of the most important private health companies in Argentina, the projects goal was to unify processes and knowledge bases into one system. Given the size of the project, a team of 20 developers, 10 QA testers, 3 DBAs and several functional people was assembled. Complex performance issues solving including refactoring of a critical module, greatly accelerating its processing. Experience with Tapestry, Hibernate, Spring, Sybase, web services, JMS, SOA, etc. Mentoring of new members of the team including systems architecture.



# **Technical Stack**

Java 8/9 **JavaScript Python** Go

Spring Postgres/Postgis

Kafka - Kafka Streams

RabbitMQ Cassandra ElasticSearch Spark Docker Ansible **VueJS NodeJS AngularJS** Flask **DevOps** GoCD GitlabCl

# Languages

Native Spanish Fluent English Fluent French

Basic Portuguese, Italian and Greek

# **Education**

Systems Engineering Universidad CAECE - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional

March. 2005 - December 2009 Buenos Aires, Argentina (Incomplete)

## **Certifications**

Sun Certified Developer For Java Web Services (SCDJWS)2008 Sun Certified Programmer for Java (SCJP)2008 Apache Certified Cassandra Architect (License V2.1-0080)2016

# References

Jean-Christophe Meillaud

CTO @ Scanbots

ic@houseofagile.com

**Manuel Deval** 

manuel.deval@gmail.com

Software Architect @ Carrefour

**Damien Kerbart** 

damien@kerbart.com

Software Engineer & Scrum Master @

**SACEM** 



Arnaud Morin
Software Engineer & Scrum Master @
SACEM

morin.arnaud@gmail.com

**Holly Pease** hpease@google.com Manager @ Google **Matthew Simmons** mpsimmon@google.com Tech Manager @ Google **Andres Melendez** amelendez@gmail.com Software Architect - Data Engineer @ Google thomasliasn@gmail.com **Thomas Eliassen** Software Engineer @ IBM Stella Goreico stella.goreico@gmail.com Manager @ Accenture